hi it's product tear down and play
around time today we've got a nice bit
of Kit this is National instruments are
their virtual bench so thank you very
much National instruments for sending
this one in this is the topof the line
model comes in two different models this
is the uh well they don't have the model
number written on the front strange
anyway it's the VB 834 this is the 300
MHz 4 channel model it's also available
in the VB 812 unit which is the 100 MHz
two chnnel model and guess what it is
take a look at all the different
functions here we've got a 4 channel uh
scope this one is 300 MHz as I said uh
build-in function generator it's got
external trigger which is nice so we got
the four channels plus the external
trigger it is a mixed signal
oscilloscope as it said so we've got a
16 channel uh mixed signal scope we've
got a power supply look at this
beautiful binding post here the Lesser
model the 100 MHz 2 channel does does
not have these binding POS it still has
a DC power supply but it has little uh
Phoenix contact connectors uh which are
fiddly and annoying I like The Binding
post on here so it's got a plusus 25v 1
amp power supply perfect for opamps and
things like that it's got a 6vt 3 amp
Supply adjustable up to that um and it's
got the Main's Earth uh grounding point
it's got a 5 1/2 digit multier built in
as well and it's got digital IO as well8
Channel digital IO so it's basically a
complete workbench in one kit and I'll
give you one guess what Market is
designed for yes the educational Market
where they buy this thing and the
students have everything they need in
one box like this beautiful and it's
designed with connectivity in mind so
it's got the ethernet land standard of
course and it's got USB as well and but
it's also got Wi-Fi build-in comes with
the antenna so you can connect uh
through to your PC or your uh tablet so
you can control this thing either away
and just Mains input and it's got one of
those Kensington lock things uh valuable
for the classroom where uh yeah um
students can wander off with these
things so H got to lock it down so what
am I expecting from this thing well the
same thing from every National
instrument product it's going to be
welld designed well manufactured super
high quality the software is going to be
uh competent and uh complete and it's
going to be high priced how high priced
this one is uh the 300 MHz 4 channel
unit we've got here is 6 Grand
US woo hang on I I'm feeling a bit laded
but the 100 MHz two channel model is a
more reasonable 2 Grand but you know if
you compare that to a scope for example
you know modern Scopes have uh you know
they'll have four channels they'll have
the function generator build in they'll
have mix signal everything else and
that's you know it's getting towards on
par with a regular bench uh scope and
certainly it's well above the price of
um you know other USB scopes on the
market but that's it's designed for a
more niche market designed for that
educational Market the educational
institutions wouldn't be paying that uh
they'd be paying a lot less they'd order
you know hundreds of the things getting
a real good deal but it's all in one
unit all of the functionality it's very
very nice and I'm sure the software is
going to work pretty well it's got nice
um feet on it lovely and it feels real
like a real top quality instrument
and smells like a quality instrument too
and yeah the build quality of the case
and everything else is just beautiful it
really is absolutely stunning what's
that there you go we got some uh
compliance rubbish and uh there it is
the VB
834 and they got fuse access on the
bottom for the multimeter of course so
you know what we say here on the EV blog
don't turn on take it apart first up we
got proper HRC fuses in here CRA brand
no worries got a small little M 205 in
there for the low current one but hey
that's fine and dandy no
worries one thing to note no Auto probe
interface so it can't Auto detect uh x
10 probes all right let's pop the hood
on this thing uh this feels like diecast
alloy this feels very nice but taada
we're in like Flynn um we don't have
much on the bottom there I like that
plastic cover that's really quite nice
around the whole multimeter uh section
which is fantastic so they're using that
as like um is that like a you know a
blast shield in case anything uh you
know blows up in the meter because you
know that that's common people you know
students are using the probes probe and
everything willy-nilly and uh yeah if
anything's going to blow it's probably
going to be the um multimeter inputs uh
so yeah that's that's really quite nice
there's no shielding uh reason for that
it's not uh it's not conductive at all
so that's just really neat I like it h
and yep it looks like we got a is that a
diecast alloy bottom that just feels
beautiful but look at the RF uh contact
that they've got stuck on here and that
mates up with the exposed pad here but
check out the ground plane Separation on
here look V stitched all the way around
there yeah they're really serious they
really know how to lay out boards at
National instruments that's what you'd
expect so yeah that's just that's
excellent so it looks like we have
mostly uh power supply type stuff on the
bottom here these look like mosfets down
here we've got the inductors of course
all dead giveaways so uh yeah it's you
know we' got some current sense
resistors up there have we so it's
pretty much all power supp supplies yep
there we go we got some opto couplers
there happening I think but yeah just
miscellaneous bypass and uh power supply
business and of course each section is
going to have its own like local
regulation so this is going to be local
regulation over here this will have some
more regulation here this little section
up the front for your digital IO has its
own little um you know triple 17
regulator up there most likely so it's
all separate very nice by the way it's a
fairly decent uh wattage power supply as
well plus - 25 volts at an amp there's
50 wats right there thank you very much
and here we go the top cover's coming
off I just love the feel of this thing
and it's it comes apart beautifully it's
beautifully designed oh look at that
once again diecast alloy top on it with
the RF shield in there absolutely
brilliant and well there's not much on
this well we're we're been mooned we're
looking at the bottom side of the uh top
board so yeah they've actually looks
like they flipped this upside down but
uh here's your individual uh channels
they're not shielded that's rather uh
interesting to see for 350 megahertz
maybe they are on the top side but the
bottom side here doesn't have any
shielding so that is rather interesting
so obviously the um 100 I I I would
guess that the 350 MHz model is going to
be different to the 100 MHz model
because it's two channels um so right
there off the bat and I think that's a
different physical configuration for the
bnc's and stuff like that so they
probably have an entirely different
board yeah it's marked VB um 8034 so
yeah it's not like a generic uh thing
now how can you not be impressed with
this build quality just ah just oozes
quality it really does um look at the uh
nice uh bundling of the uh power cables
down here coming out the switch mode
power supply massive fery bead on there
uh that each bundle is individually heat
shrunk or is that no yeah it looks like
they might might have individual oh no
is that no that's taping no they they
they're actually taped wow old school um
but yeah nice switch mode power supply
you need that in here of course we're
not going to get a linear uh power
supply for our main uh output you know
for our 50 W plus uh power supply output
so definitely not going to get that this
board down here is interesting look at
this at first I thought oh it must have
something on the front panel something
like that but there's nothing on the
front panel here there's absolutely
nothing so I don't know what these slots
are doing here um it looks like it's
just an interconnect board to connect
this top board here through the top
acquisition board through to the bottom
board down there um it's quite strange H
and that's our mix signal digital input
we got extensive Dio protection on there
check that out yep uh positive and
negative uh protection per uh input
liking the way this case goes together I
tell you what I think this front panel
it's just going to pull off here yeah
look at that and it's there's a
connector down in there which I can just
front panel connector aha there's the
trick that's what it is it looks like we
got some voltage that this is used as a
voltage sense line coming back by the
looks of it or is it um maybe output on
off control I can see some extra stuff
down there cuz you might be noting well
where's the diode protection on the uh
power supply you know the reverse Doo
protection well I believe it's on the
other uh side there so I'm assuming that
that's what this does is this is a sense
line which uh connects through to there
I have to undo them more to have a look
and if you were concerned about the
potential lack of shake proof washes on
there don't be I had a real hard time
getting those uh nuts off they've
obviously got some sort of clear um uh
Loctite type uh stuff on them so yeah
serious business and if you want to see
what guilding the Lily is well take a
look at this they could have they had
one screw here to hold this board in in
addition to all the uh binding posts
across there and look they've gone to
the effort to put a threaded insert into
that very nice anyway it turns out this
board has a lot more more on it and I
would have realized if I actually uh
turned the thing on before I took it
apart oops um look we got some LEDs in
here and they actually go through the
front panel so the front panel must have
like a
semi-transparent uh thing on it um so
yeah they're like status leads and
things like that but they're not marked
on the front um so they just light up
and Flash and do things so we got a bit
of uh drivery action happening there
there's a there's a diode I told you
about for protection there we got a
couple of ceramic bypass caps on the
output got ourselves a nice resetable
fuse in there by the looks of it and we
got some fuse protection here on the
output I don't they they don't look like
resetable fuses they look like you know
onetime SMD fuses that blow so I hope
they've done their homework on that
because you wouldn't want to the
students to short the outputs and blow
these things but I'm sure they have this
is National instruments right they know
what they're doing so probably for
extreme gross over loads and things like
that if the uh constant current uh
output you know circuitry limit failed
or something like that and for the main
event we will now attempt to lift this
board off there's a uh looks like a PCI
uh Express connector up here which is
very common in board to board stuff
these days so I need to lift that but
that should come out they got a nice
slot there for the uh little micro coax
coming from the antenna connector on the
back that's very nice attention to
detail to keep it in place doesn't flap
around in the breeze so you know
somebody was thinking the person who
laid out the board must have been
instructed or was you know like they
worked together to with the mechanical
people okay we need a a uh uh coax on
the back here for the antenna and well
you know you didn't have to put that
slot in there you have to know that that
slot when it went together as a system
that slot had to go in there so they
would have probably you know 3D modeled
all this and everything else but that's
very nice anyway here is the main event
I don't think there's any other cables
Tada and well that's the bottom side but
oh hello sailor hello sailor look at
that
woo wow is that a gorgeous heat sink or
what so this gets rather interesting now
this heat sink here is for the
oscilloscope section as you can see
here's our scope inputs here and our
arbitrary waveform generator and
everything else yeah it's 350 MHz so you
know it's going to get reasonably warm
but that you know that seems a
disproportionate size heat sync but
they're really going to town thermally
on that so that's absolutely uh
brilliant but have a look up here you'll
notice well where's all our you know our
big 50 wat uh power supply coming from
all that you know usually you see uh you
know some decent heat sink in for a
reasonable uh size bench Supply which
this one has um it's obviously all
happening in this switch mode can here
this is not only the main stuff but
remember this is the output going
directly to that front panel binding
post for the power supply so it's all
coming from up here like this so
obviously look we've only got some tiny
little surface mount heat sinks in here
like this on these surface mount parts
nothing fancy at all you remember you
saw some uh Power stuff on the other
side of this board when we first opened
the thing as well but there were no heat
sinks on that so that's the entirety of
the heat sinks for all the power supply
it's absolutely incredible so you got
plusus 25 volts at an amp and also 6
volts at 3 amps as well so they're
obviously um controlling the switch mode
output you know feeding back uh to the
switch mode output to get minimize the
drop across the output voltage
Regulators so that they can get away
with such a small uh heat sink like this
so for say a 25 uh plusus 25 volt
maximum output this thing isn't going to
be output in say you know 28 volts or
something like that and then dropping
the whole lot across there you wouldn't
have enough heat sinking at all you
would need you know something serious
like this going on so obviously they're
using a tracking uh switch mode
regulator in here which is also
providing power for the main board as
well you can see we got some isolation
Transformers here these are Halo brand
TG 21s they've got uh they're like a
compatible one for like your more
traditional pulse brand uh Transformers
they got another little baby one of that
oh sorry for the glare little baby one
of that inside here as well for the
multimeter section so that's doing some
isolation actually I got a bit
sidetracked there it's uh more obvious
when I think about it for a uh second
what we've got here is rather than uh
control the main switch mode output here
and use that as like a tracking uh
pre-regulator uh kind of thing um
because I thought like originally these
might have been uh low Dropout linear
Regulators on the output and I believe
they are but what's going on here is
actually this section here with our
three isolation Transformers is the uh
switch mode uh converter you'll know
that we've got our diode outputs there
and we've got our bulk our bulk ceramic
decoupling on the input and if we flip
it over we've actually got there we go
the these look like our primary side uh
Drive transistors right here and uh we
got some extra uh output filter in there
we' got everything hunky dory so what it
is is they're using this as a um a
switching uh pre-regulator and then I
believe it looks like that they're using
uh the outputs um these low Dropout
linear Regulators on the outputs which
is why they you know they might only be
dissipating like a watt each regardless
of the output voltage just do want clean
it up because you could have a direct
switch mode um output but then it's not
all that clean and well I don't think
National instruments would do that they
you know most likely I don't know you'd
have to check the uh specs and things
like that it'd be obvious whether or not
they've got a uh linear uh low Dropout
regulator on the output just based on
the switching noise figures and things
like that so yeah these are low Dropout
linear Regulators probably dissipating
like a what each maximum or something
like that which is why they can get away
with such small heat sings Here it looks
like we've got some um are they our
current sense resistors there they're
most likely uh tapping those off but uh
yep and you can see it actually coming
out here here we go here we go follow
the traces follow the money follow the
money as deep throat said here we go all
the way over and that goes over to our
uh they're our two tracers so these
would be our plus minus uh 25 volt uh
regulators and this poor little Lonesome
guy over here will be the uh fault
output job and I just love the board to
board interconnect I love you know PCI
Express I've used them myself for
various uh board to board interconnects
and test instrument interfaces and all
sorts of things they're cheap they're
reliable High number of insertions and
just you know great stuff and they're
cheap you know standardized and they're
going to be around forever and they're
just brilliant Bard to board
interconnects and then you just design a
little Riser board like that to join the
two boards some nice big standoffs this
is beautiful engineering and it gets
even better as we saw on the bottom side
we've also got this custom uh injection
molded plastic uh blast Shield as well
on the entire multimeter section they're
really going to down guilding the Lily
like I'm surprised the inside of this
ain't goldplated now this board is
interesting one of the things I noticed
is uh look heat sink detect number four
up here um so I that makes me think that
there um and wouldn't surpris me
actually that their uh temper what
detect means is that they likely uh
temperature sense in that heat sink so
it's probably there maybe they've got
some circuitry under there at that uh
point I don't see anything on the bottom
side there really any uh detection stuff
but I I suspect that's what's happening
I don't see the other ones uh marked 1 2
3 and four but is definitely number four
there H and down there for the digital
IO nothing much happening that little
chippy there is actually a TI CC 384
it's marked I believe that's a little TI
microcontroller not uh surprising at all
to uh see that there that would be doing
its own thing uh controlling the um IO
here and then you can have the software
talk to that so that makes complete
sense as for the multimeter section here
clearly these two cans here are the
analog to digital uh converters oh why
they've got two maybe they're using a oh
can you measure voltage and current at
the same time perhaps H that would be
nice um I haven't checked the uh
functionality of thing but that would
make sense with the uh 2 adcs we can see
the nice little uh surface mount current
shunt uh down there that would be I
think is it 10 amps capable I don't know
it's several amps anyway and uh there's
a lattice um CLD happening in there just
to uh control the uh conversion and
things like that so let's go all the way
with lb J here and take off this plastic
blast shield on the top and the metal
cans here pop those off and bingo what
do we got all our circuitries under here
under here we've got uh a bunch of uh
resistors now they're most likely
because they're near this is actually
the positive input jacket the current
stuff is over here you can see all the
current shunts and big huge beefy traces
so this is um an input high voltage uh
divider here and there's the other side
right there I'll crack out the uh
microscope and have a look at some part
numbers and here's another angle of
those uh input high voltage networking
see all these resistors here here we go
they serial chaining all of those that
gives you a high voltage because each
one only you know might have like a 150
200 volts uh compliance so you put them
all in series in a string like that and
bingo you got yourself a high voltage
input resistor no worries whatsoever you
can see some guard tracers guard rings
going around there very nice they know
what they're doing at National
instruments that's for sure because they
do lots of ton of high-end uh
instruments and things like that you
know measurement instruments you know
24bit adcs you know plug in acquisition
cards that are ridiculous performance
and things like that so yep they know
exactly what they're doing and the
chippies let's have a look and we've got
ourselves an adg 1308 and a 1309 there
they're just uh some you know
half reasonable mxes fast switching
stuff primarily designed for video type
use so I don't know how fast the switch
in is on this thing I don't know if
that's a requirement but anyway they
decided to use those just a few other
miscellaneous jobes around here I'm not
going to bother uh decoding I don't
think there's anything too interesting
there there's another adg
1309 marks in there let's have a look at
these others and might be hard to see
but down in there we got some Analog
Devices ad
46 uh 10s and they're uh very very
Schmick there's another one down there
uh very very schmi oh that one's upside
down all the electrons are going to fall
out oops um very Schmick jfet uh low
noise opamps low everything super duper
whizbang Bob's your uncle opamps oh nice
and there's our voltage reference right
there Analog Devices ad 586 Precision 5
reference no worries whatsoever got to
have some 4,000 series or in this case
74 HCT series
4052 uh Marx no worries whatsoever and
we got another one we got one up there
if it's 're going to focus yeah
4053 nice you still use them like 40
years later brilliant but I certainly
came a gut on that prediction didn't I I
thought they were possibly duel um adcs
under there I didn't think about the
mxes and the high voltage input and all
that sort of stuff duh it's probably
obvious if I gave it some more thought
so obviously they must be implementing
an ADC inside this lattice CP here cuz
there's nothing else this is going to be
one of these um digital isolators you
can actually see the ground uh through
the board there you can see the lack of
copper in there so they got all the
ground plane over here they' got the
ground plane here obviously separated
going under the chip there so that's
going to be a digital isolator don't
even have to read the part number on
that puppy not that I can on the screen
here you can probably read that in HD
but uh yeah that L semi they must be
rolling their own ADC with that so
that's obviously going to be some sort
of dual slopey type integrator uh
converter something like that as for the
uh rest of it the power supply side of
things um I won't go into a huge am
amount of detail suffice to say there
you go we' got some surface mount uh
packages under there but uh that's about
oh she wrote lots of uh bulk uh
decoupling there with your Ceramics and
things like that but yeah got some
isolation Transformers as I said o doing
a fly over
oo using Dave steady
cam well you probably know what I'm
going to say about that isn't that
gorgeous
wow beautifully laid out it just ooes
quality nice shielding strap there on
the Transformer coilcraft inductor over
here we got our common mode choke on the
UT got our protection and our uh various
class caps they're all celastic down
there's our diode Bridge there they' C
celastic that down to the cap in here
obviously it's not doing a huge amount
our main DC cap will take a look at but
uh the main um output primary transforma
there looks absolutely fantastic those
caps look super classy um there's a
couple of uh exra marks on here so that
would be some sort of um production uh
operator uh testing something like that
they've just marked them off that it's
uh fully passed but that layout is just
oh just oozes quality and if you're
wondering about the Earth pin flapping
around in the breeze over here you
needn't be concerned of course because
Tada there is the earth pin there solded
onto the bottom and uh that is connected
directly to the ground plane on the
whole blinking lot so yes of course
everything is Main's Earth referenced
except the multimeter of course that'll
be completely floating and yes they have
rubber compliant mount on the fan here I
don't know what brand fan is I'd have to
take it out couldn't be
bothered and of course the main caps are
nichy con no worries and the output caps
no worries at all we got the Big M there
that stands for MATA I.E Panasonic
Beauty and you don't think we're going
to finish just tear down without taking
a look under here do you nah I don't
either let's
[Music]
go and for the main
event the main event is me failing to
get that off um I've got all the screws
and out um there this thing ain't
budging I can only presume that I'm
going to have to wiggle it because the
surf possibly the surface tension of the
uh thermal compound on there is causing
it to stick I can give it a little
wiggle
but jeez don't bust it ah trap for young
players look at that Bloody double-sided
sponge tape on under there by the looks
of it what a pain in the butt well
that's actually likely to be uh thermal
sponge I
believe adhesive thermal sponge it's
definitely something's got to be
adhesive because I'm putting a lot of
force on this thing either trying to uh
lever it up or uh you know trying to
wiggle it side to side I'm putting a lot
of force on it and that's barely barely
budging wow anyway actually quite
surprised that they got the Wi-Fi chips
set there's the little uh micro coax
output for the um cable going into the
antenna on the back I'm surprised I've
actually got that on the same board as
the acquisition board I mean granted
this is I believe this is the external
trigger uh this is your AWG output and
your four scope channels are uh here but
still you know like on the same board in
the same area but they know what they're
doing they've separated the ground
planes power supplies everything's hunky
dory nothing you can't fix with a bit of
Leever screwdriver Force here we go yeah
we're going to be in like Flynn in a
second hang on hold on to your
hats wow look at that awesome and
there's our evil thermal uh adhesive
stuff really great stuff you can see the
imprints of the uh chips which are
probably the analog to digital
converters will check out so they're
actually using that to transfer the heat
uh straight through but obviously
they've got um you know D cutouts here
that directly mate with like this big
application processor here look at that
Beast oh there we go there's a xylin
zinc there oh beautiful yeah you need
some serious fpga combo arm horsepower
and that zinc's going to deliver in
Spades so yep there we go um actually
they might be thermal dedicated thermal
pads on there anyway they have to get
this is the sponge um stuff is going to
be higher thermal resistance than the
either the direct uh contact or having
the dedicated uh you know thermal pad uh
thermal grease something like that so
but it's still you know they do a
reasonable job of getting the heat out
and there's our main Beast look at that
oh that massive dye in there is I see
zyink and we'll give that a bit of a
wiper d with our
isopr
alcohol get that off there we should be
able to hopefully get a nice
shiny part number and there she is a
zyink kintex 7 XC 7K 160t that is going
to be a beast if you want to ask the
price on that puppy you probably can't
afford it wonder if it's on Digi key and
sure enough 4
$96 us of course Yankee money um one off
price none of this uh quantity discount
rubbish um and B Digi key have 128 in
stock no worries well it turns out that
heat sink detect thing is not actually
detecting temperature cuz you'll see a
little Trace running off there it's
obviously detecting that it's physically
there like it's connected uh down to a
ground point or something so it's like
checking that the heat the heat sinker
is like a shorten strap so yeah why are
they that Keen to know that the heat
sink's in place I mean what is it just
suddenly going to work loose and vanish
grow legs and vanish I don't know now
the interesting thing about this is not
only do we have this Beast of an fpga
here this uh connect uh device here
couple hundred buck uh sorry $500 worth
in one off Cory we also got another
zyink zinc here and it's it's basic
Bally a similar uh you know kind of
family uh and this one of course has the
arm processor built-in plus the fpga
fabric whereas this one uh is just a a
big ass fpga but this zinc on its own
we're looking at $150 to $200 part here
as well and we've seen this in other
Scopes just this on its own is enough to
implement this scope so what they're
doing here why they've got a combination
of both of those um I'm not entirely
sure like this scope I believe um
although I haven't powered it up yet I
believe it doesn't even have like
intensity uh greater display and you
know uh do all like it doesn't do any
realtime fft or anything like that as
far as I'm aware um so really this zinc
on its own is more than capable enough
of doing this we've seen lots of other
uh low to mid-range scopes with just
this in uh tear down so why they got two
and interestingly look I mean if you
follow the once again follow the money
here from this USB connector down here
the tracers from the USB are going all
the way over to here here's our USB
transceiver here and it's obviously tied
into the zinc you can tell but it's the
physical location there's no reason why
you'd put it there and then have it go
into here you know like into uh this PCI
and go somewhere else it just doesn't uh
make any sense at all so clearly this is
they're using this arm processor here to
implement all of the USB um like the
communications uh interface with the
software and things like that and uh of
course the main uh connects fpga here is
doing all of the uh oscilloscope uh
processing itself so and the other
interesting part is I can't see any
highspeed interface between the two look
we've got a uh we've got a different no
it's not even a barely not even a
differential pair I don't know some
tracers running over there there's
nothing on the bottom side here between
the two chips there's a ton of
decoupling and everything else but they
could be running them on inner uh layers
this is at least a uh a four layer board
but uh basically there's you know no
huge big parallel Communications between
these two that we can at least see on
the top um so I'm not not exactly sure
why now Not only would this do all the
uh system stuff it's probably like
running who knows what little it could
be running an OS or it could be running
some uh custom thing in the arm
processor there it's more than capable
of running anything you uh can imagine
um I figur maybe they're using the fpga
fabric in this as well to also run the
arbitrary uh waveform gen but it's all
the way over here here's the argen
circuitry over here this is the trigger
out this is the ARB uh gen output here
you can see the output resistors here
and uh there's probably um that's I
don't know maybe a Dack a reference or
something under there um but yeah that's
all the way over there but yeah it could
be could be getting the data right
across the board it just doesn't seem to
make sense from a layout uh point of
view anyway so H I don't know but hey
maybe the connect has enough uh Grunt in
it to uh Drive the arbitary waveform
generator as well that's I wouldn't put
it past it cuz the good thing about fpga
is that you can dedicate just a part of
the chip part of the fabric to doing
that individual task it doesn't take
away uh from the other task of running
of doing the sampling system for the
oscilloscope here now this particular
model of the kch 7 here has 160k uh
logic Elements which is one of the lower
parts in the family and it's only 500
bucks one off cost go figure anyway it's
got 2 megabits of distributed RAM and
it's got 11 Meg bits of block Ram so um
if you divide that by eight that's more
than a Meg and this thing the spec for
this thing is one Meg um not sure if
it's one I think it's one Meg per
channel so this actually has enough
block Ram in it to do all the storage
locally in there but hey look we got
some extra memory here and here and on
the bottom as well are they DDR 3s yep
these are DDR3 but hold on to your hats
these are one gig bit that's
128 megabytes Meg samples per chip
there's four chips that makes sense we
got four channels dedicating one per
Channel but they got 64 they can have 64
Meg samples on this thing and the spec
I'm pretty sure only says one and the
ADC for ADC afficionados I know you're
out there this is the ADC 08d 1520 a
family that we've seen in oscilloscopes
before very common U basically purpose
designed for this sort of uh task this
is an 8bit uh converter 1.5 gig samples
per second dual Channel so that's why
we've got two of these puppies on here
so none of this multiplexing rubbish you
get the full 1.5 gig samples per Channel
nice but these are actually capable of
being interleaved or multiplexed uh so
you can get double sample rate on a
single uh input Channel if you uh
configure It That Way 3 gig samples per
second but uh the spec doesn't do that
so once again just like the memory up
here they seem to be gilding the Lily
it's you Know It This Hardware is
capable of much more than what I think
uh they're actually uh making use of in
this thing and I'm not sure if you can
see the part number on that but even if
you could may not make much sense it's I
believe it's actually a TI LMX
281e and no surprises for guessing given
where it is right between the two adc's
it's uh the PLL we need to generate our
clock it's the frequency synthesizer vco
PL whatever you want to call it and yeah
it's a bit of a beast and it's cap and
it's generating the sample clock for the
ADC now let's take a look at the front
end here here's the BNC and take a look
at this little ceramic package here
isn't that a Bobby desla look at that
it's a
crf5 have a look at the data sheet here
and it is a it's a ripper it's a 7 Gig
uh high frequency read Reay so they're
obviously using yeah like once again
Guild of the Lily here um using this RF
re read relay to uh switch in extra uh
extra input dividers down in here that's
spared no expense really um that's just
absolutely crazy so anyway check out
what we have here
Tada National Instruments
Part maybe we can decode that part
number I don't know they're probably
like it's most likely maybe an
off-the-shelf thing that they've got
rebranded National instruments not sure
why they do that they haven't done it on
any others but I don't know could it be
their own sort of custom front end Asic
I don't know they're probably big enough
to you know expense to to uh wear the
expense on uh doing that but anyway uh
yeah this will probably be our output
differential driver here I haven't
looked at the uh part number on that but
that's probably driving the ADC or
something like that but yeah it's got
all the requisite bits for a scope uh
front end pretty much and this is a 350
gig one so let's uh let's flip this over
have a look at the bottom is there much
doing here what is that thing
3378 what's that I don't know nothing
special but like I said uh earlier
before I'm a bit surprised that they
didn't uh Shield the bottom of this
thing but they don't need to like it's
right up against that you know that
diecast case and everything else like
you know but they've guilded the Lily
everywhere else so yeah just little Tad
surprising there but yeah no problems
they're spared no expense on that uh
front end I'm sure it works
spectacularly so that is some of the
most expensive and granti uh stuff we've
seen in a you know any even you know
some quite high-end uh scope tear down
so it's more than capable of doing the
job and you can see where the uh in this
case the six grand uh retail cost go you
know these chips aren't particularly
cheap they wouldn't be making these in
the millions so you know they'd be
making them in the thousands or
something like that so not really huge
volume let's take a look at our arbitary
waveform generator circuitry pop the
hood on the can here and uh look we just
got got some caps some inductors some
resistor we've just got an LC filter in
there that's it that's all she wrote
Under that can they are really going to
town once again just to Shield that
filter and those inductors nice and
there's our duck yep uh Analog Devices
of course what else would you expect in
there um one of the TX stack parts and
that's a 14bit uh 125 Meg sample per
second so yep it's doing the business
and then yeah we've just got uh buffers
amplifiers filters and everything else
after that and on the output here we've
got two THS 3091 um highspeed output uh
driver exactly what you'd expect we' got
our output termination resistors there
we' got ourselves a poly switch fuse and
a little bit more filtering and Bob's
your uncle now this is interesting this
connector here does not poke out the
back of the uh box so only the ethernet
and the USB here so what that pupp is
doing I don't know some sort of uh test
connector something like that doesn't
seem to be going you know internal
layers
probably half of them are ground and uh
so yeah is that I would assume some sort
of production test connector type thing
maybe and here's our mix signal logic
analyzer part we've got ourselves some
comparators there I won't even bother
looking up I know they programmable
comparators I know I think believe
they've got thresholds allow you to set
thresholds on each one extensive RC um
filtering here or you know compensation
the capacitors would be compensating the
input uh the input divider and you're
going to need that this is you know a
reasonable 100 mahz uh maximum frequency
input one gig sample per second for
timing mode of course State not even
sure it might I think there is an
external clock on this so it could do
state analysis as well uh what that
means is that it uses an external clock
to actually do the uh sampling I think
that one the external clock is 100 MHz
maximum so there you have it that's the
national instruments virtual bench to
worn down and it is a Bobby desla is it
not um and it's well you can you pay
6,000 bucks for it but you're getting
quality in here that's uh for sure and
yes it is an expensive beast but uh it's
all comes down to how well it works in
the uh software so I'm this video has
been too long what is it 3540 minutes or
something so I'll leave that to another
one so click here somewhere if you want
to watch the video of actually uh having
to play around with this thing and as
always I've got highres tear down photos
over on evev blog.com so uh yeah I'll
probably link that in somewhere down
below catch you next
time
for